ESTHER C. BAILEY-BASS

Professional, Strategist, Leader, Coach and Team Player

152 Sophie Drive • Antioch, TN 37013 • 615.406.1024 • ebaileybass@gmail.com

Background

My professional background represents exciting and challenging opportunities, layered with varied skills and talents which have lead to success in diverse arenas. I am well-versed in non-profit and for-profit sales, marketing and fundraising with 12 years of sales growth experience for a local public radio station. I have expansive knowledge, skills and talent in community relations, new business development and special projects, public relations, and event planning and execution. As a leader, strategist and professional, I believe in the greatness of teams and individuals.

Why me?

Big thinking and collaboration inspire and motivate me, igniting my curiosity and passion for learning. I believe that a positive attitude coupled with a willingness to learn leads to excellence, generates resourcefulness, expands possibilities, and increases the pursuit for change and growth. I am a natural creative and critical thinker who embraces new challenges with enthusiasm and fortitude. As a goal-oriented, results driven professional, I am resolute when working for a purpose or toward an objective.

SUMMARY OF EXPERTISE

BUSINESS TO BUSINESS SALES / BRAND MARKETING

Sales and Marketing Professional with 10+ years demonstrated successful sales and marketing experience in time-sensitive, fast paced environments; experienced in driving company growth and reputation for fostering successful professional relationships; and a detailed-oriented, self-starter possessing excellent written, oral and interpersonal communication skills.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- · Consultative sales method
- New business development
- High-impact sales presentations
- Account management skills
- Team building and leadership qualities

- Successful closing techniques
- Promotional copywriting
- Internal/external client care
- Strong product knowledge
- Excellent organization skills

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Nashville Public Radio and Public Radio Partners

Public Radio Partners (PRP) is a privately owned business providing outsourced underwriting sales departments to public broadcasting stations. In calendar year 2009 PRP generated \$16 million in underwriting revenue for its client stations.

Corporate Support Representative, 2000 - Present

- Annual revenue billing in excess of \$400,000
- Proven account growth resulting in 20% increased revenue
- Consistently exceeded set revenue goals for 7 consecutive years
- Reduced account attrition after re-distribution
- Generate qualified sales referrals from clients, cold calling, and email prospecting
- Create successful sales presentations from client needs assessment and utilization of market and industry data
- Maintain strong client relationships through consistent communications and superior client service

Xerox Business Services

The world's leading enterprise for business process and document management.

Client Liaison/Customer Relations Customer Service Professional, 1999 – 2000 (Temp to hire position)

- Organized customer service department by developing new quality assurance procedures and guidelines to improve efficiency, quality control and on-time delivery
- Created a system to solicit client feedback to quickly resolve client complaints and ensure topquality service and satisfaction
- Improvements based on client feedback resulted in higher client satisfaction survey results
- Provided clerical support of document proofreading, duplication, collating and distribution of presentation materials for easy retrieval and distribution and further ensured accuracy and ontime delivery

The Tennessean

The Tennessean is a broad-based information company serving Middle Tennesseans as their leading source local news and information.

Marketing Assistant, 1997 – 1999

- Assisted in all aspects of marketing department operations, including support, development and distribution of marketing and sales materials on deadline
- Created concept for employee newsletter "Broadway Beat", coordinated volunteer writing staff and editorial process and distributed monthly newsletter consistently and timely.

Classified Account Executive, 1995 – 1997

 Generated revenue from existing and new accounts through display advertising sales, classified line ads, special sections, special editions and special ad promotions.

EDUCATION

Belmont University, Nashville, TN

MBA Certificate Program

The University of Akron, Akron, OH

Bachelor of Arts, Business and Organization Communication

SOFTWARE

MAC & PC Literate

Microsoft Word, Power Point, Outlook; Arbitron (ListenerPC, MarketPC) The Media Audit, ACT! Database, Marketron/WICKS Broadcast Traffic Software

AWARDS

Nashville Public Radio & Public Radio Partner, \$1,000,000 Team Sales Award International Association of Business Communicators, Gold Pen Excel Award Recipient The Tennessean, Director's Circle

PROFESSIONAL AND VOLUNTEER ORGANIZATIONS

The YWCA of Middle Tennessee

- o Board Member 2007-Present
- o Executive Board Member 2008-2009

CABLE Member 2000 – Present

o Board Member 2004-2005

CABLE

Athena Judge December 2012 – January 2013

Young Leaders Council (YLC)

o Graduate 2006

Maxwell Place Homeowners Association

o Board 2008-2010